Denmark, May 1945
Five year German occupation ends.
You there! Stop! Yes you!
What is this? That's not yours.
Do you understand?
What's the matter?
Do you have a problem? Huh?
What do you have now?
Go back home! Get out!
This is not your flag!
Please! Please! Stop!
Get up! Up, I said!
Here! Take your cap and get out.
Asshole!
Get out! Get out, I said!
This is my country! Do you understand? Get out!
You're not welcome here!
Get lost! This is my country! Understood?
Get them out of here, man.
Yes, sir. Sergeant.
Land Of Mine
I'm Capt.Ebbe Jensen from the
Danish Pioneer Corps.
For those of you who do not
know why you are here:
I have been brought to Denmark
to clean up after the war.
Denmark is not your friend.
You should understand that.
Don't expect Danes to receive you with open arms.
No one wants Germans here.
And I'm here only for one reason:
Clear the Danish west coast of German land mines.
Mines that have been planted here.
There are approximately 2.2 million
mines along the Danish west coast...
more than, in all European countries put together.
Someone must have thought the
Allied invasion would take place here.
What a shame, whoever had that idea.
And too bad for you.
Who has seen or handled a land mine before?
Has anyone tried to disarm one?
Who has seen this before?
That's the most common mine.
For maximum effect, mines are buried
15 to 20 cm in the sand...
which makes them relatively easy to find.
You just lost your hands.
Come on. We have no time for self-pity.
You're dead.
Here, we have been shown our first death.
If you don't see your family again,
will you be the first one to die?
No.
I can't hear you.
I will not be the first to die.
I'm happy to hear that. Again.
Dead again.
The mines here are not duds.
If you do anything wrong,
you will either die or be seriously injured.
Is that understood?
Yes, sir. Captain!
Good. Come here.
You are the first man.
Yes, sir. Captain.
Now.
Next.
Excellent. That was fast.
Faster!
Next.
Excellent.
Faster!
Come on!
Others would have long ago
done all mines by now.
Have you fallen asleep?
Sir. Captain, request permission to retrieve him.
Under no circumstance.
Fuck this!
I'm coming in.
Let the mine be as it's.
I can do this.
Get up, soldier. Get up!
No, I can do this.
Soldier! Get up!
No, please! I know I can handle it.
Cover your ears.
Next.
When the mine is disarmed...
Elisabeth. Come here.
Come here, baby.
Are you soldiers?
Answer me, you dirty swine!
Yes, sir. Sergeant!
Fall on a rank! Now!
Hurry up! Now, now, now, now!
Fall on a rank!
Come on!
Attention!
Don't you understand 'Attention'?
Yes I do.
Then stand like a man!
At ease!
Name?
Marklein, sir. Sergeant.
First name?
Hermann, sir. Sergeant.
Rodolf Selke, sir. Sergeant.
Friedrich Schnurr.
Wolff what?
Johann Wolff.
Kluger.
Full name?
August Kluger.
Sir, Sergeant.
And you two? You look like brothers.
We are twins, sir. Sergeant.
Twins?
Name?
Werner and Ernst Lessner,
Sir, Sergeant.
Did I ask you?
No you did not.
Then shut up.
Pardon me.
What?
What did you say?
Pardon me.
Why are you apologizing?
Because I mentioned my brother's name.
You are apologizing?
Yes, Sir Sargent.
To hell with your excuse!
I can't pardon! Do you understand?
Yes, sir. Sergeant.
And you, little guy?
Wilhelm Lebern, sir. Sergeant.
Are you a soldier?
Yes, sir. Sergeant.
Ludwig Haffke, sir. Sergeant.
Sebastian Schumann, sir. Sergeant.
Look at me when you talk.
Helmut Morbach, sir. Sergeant.
What a fine uniform.
Have you been at war?
Yes, sir. Sergeant.
Are you crying?
No, sir. Sergeant!
What is it? Are you crying?
Are you scared?
No, sir. Sergeant!
Are you homesick?
Can everyone see the black flag out there?
Yes, sir. Sergeant.
Between the flags are 45,000 buried mines.
You must disarm and remove them.
When you are finished,
you may be allowed to go home.
Is that understood?
Yes, sir. Sergeant!
Not until they are disarmed, you can get home!
Is that understood?
Yes, sir. Sergeant!
If you disarm six mines an hour
and don't blow yourselves up,
you may go home in three months.
Is that understood?
Yes, sir. Sergeant!
You! Did you want to say something?
No, sir. Sergeant.
Are you sure?
Absolutely sure, sir. Sergeant.
You card.
Ludwig, sir. Sergeant.
Give me the map.
Can you see it?
Yes, sir!
Each field has a number.
The star and the dot show the type of mine.
Those of you who count the mines,
make sure my card is updated.
This task is as important as defusing mines.
Is that understood?
Yes, sir. Sergeant!
From the stone, mark the water
to create a safety zone.
Do I need to tell you what happens
to those who try to escape?
No, sir. Sergeant!
One, two, three, four.
One, two...
three, four.
One, two, three, four.
I have one!
I have one too!
It's not so bad here.
What will I do when I
get back to your family?
I will be a mechanic.
One of my father's friends has a good factory.
He would hire me, when I get home.
Aren't you forgetting something?
Mind your own business.
Surely he should know that his
fine future is a damn illusion.
It's no illusion.
He has already promised me.
And if...
Stop.
Should I ask would he employ an apprentice?
Yes. That would be nice.
Then we can work together.
Yes.
Should I also ask for you, Wilhelm?
Stop.
That would be nice.
The three...
Helmut.
Shut up!
Stop.
The three of us, hand in hand.
What!?
See? I think she has some food.
She has some bread.
Hi there.
What is her name?
Do you understand German?
She is hurt. See.
A soldier must always be ready to help.
I did not have a doll as a child.
I'm a boy, so I had a car.
That should make her better.
Thanks.
You are welcome.
Elisabeth!?
You'd better go.
Elisabeth! Come here, when I call for you.
What are you doing over there?
No, you know what?
I told you, don't go over to
the fishing house, right?
What is that you don't understand?
Don't you understand what I'm saying?
I'm tired of you drifting.
It's now, if you need to take a leak.
No? Get to bed.
Go now! Move!
Are you all in here?
Yes, sir. Sergeant.
Can't you talk to him?
I haven't eaten in two days.
Does no good complaining.
How do I defuse mines on an empty stomach?
It's me, Sebastian.
What do you want?
Do you know, we haven't had anything
to eat in two days, sir. Sergeant?
If we don't get some food...
So what?
Do you think I feel sorry for you?
No, sir. Sergeant.
I fucking don't care.
I don't care if you are nasty.
I know, sir. Sergeant.
I don't know when the food comes.
The Germans are not ahead of the game.
Good night, Sebastian.
Back to bed.
Put yourselves to sleep!
Get in the bed!
Psst...
Where are you going?
Shh! Just sleep now.
Are you running away?
I need to find something to eat.
He can't. I know my brother.
I saw him this morning, vomiting constantly.
Look at me when you talk to me.
Ernst?
That's right, sir. Sergeant.
Look at me!
He's right. I'm not feeling well.
If only you could allow me
to rest an hour, please.
Ernst, you know, I can't allow that.
Well I feel sick...
He may not be up for it, please sir. Sergeant.
You are a little warm,
but you can work, right?
Sir. Sergeant
What do you say, Otto?
Should we leave them to rest an hour? Shall we?
Should we let them rest?
He could pass out.
Do you think they're trying to cheat us?
What?
No, they wouldn't dare.
Well? No, they wouldn't dare.
Look at me, boys.
Back to work.
But...sir. Sergeant
Do you hear me?
Back to work, I said! Now!
Move it now!
Wilhelm? Wilhelm?
Somethings wrong.
Take off my helmet.
Take off this shit helmet.
Help me!
I want to go home.
Quiet now.
You'll be all right.
Helmut, help me to get him
away from this beach.
Help me.
You will be OK. Take it easy.
Calm down.
Hey! Help me out!
Why did you help him?
Help me!
I want to go home! I want to go home!
Calm down.
Help!
Help me! Help me!
Sir. Sergeant! We need help!
I want to go home!
Don't worry. Look at me.
It will be OK.
You'll make it.
Mother! Mother!
Sir. Sergeant, help us!
Do something! Please! Help us!
Come here! Please! Help us!
Sir. Sergeant!
Mother!
Mother! I want to go home!
Look at me. You will go home.
It will be OK. Trust me.
I don't want this anymore!
I want to go home!
I want to...I want to...
Thank you, sir. Sergeant.
What's going on?
It's my fault, sir. Sergeant.
Your fault?
It's my fault. We were...
Look at me when you talk to me!
We were so hungry last night that,
I stole some fodder from the farm.
That's why we have become ill.
As an officer it's my responsibility,
that everyone gets some food.
You have no responsibility here.
Where is your mother?
When I say there is no food here,
that's how it's.
What is this?
If they ate it, they would get sick.
It's full of rat feces. Look...
What is so funny?
Anyway, I get to ram the Germans.
What did she laugh at?
Listen, kid...
we don't speak to one another.
Is that understood?
You don't talk to me!
I ask and you answer.
And always with 'Sir, Sergeant'. Understand?
Yes, sir. Sergeant.
Why did you do something?
I was not offered anything.
Throw up!
Drink, drink, drink! Down with it! Come on!
Seawater!
Would you like to die instead?
All right, boys. Drink.
Wash yourselves.
Wash yourselves. Lower your head.
Wash yourselves good.
Down with the head.
You are good, you are good.
Come on. Here, come on. Come on. Sit.
Get to bed.
May I show you something, Sir. Sergeant?
I said, get to bed.
I want to show you something.
With this framework, its easier to clear mines.
With this the area is bounded,
so we can look for mines.
Fine! I understand. I'm not stupid.
I understand.
Take your toy and get back to bed.
I know why you hate us,
and don't care whether we get
blown up or die of hunger.
Yes. You are correct.
But it's not good that we die while
we clear the mines on the beach.
I don't care.
Take your toy and get to bed.
The beach must be cleared of mines,
is it not, sir. Sergeant?
Yes, I understand that.
Do you understand you need to get to bed now?
All I ask is you listen.
Then hurry up.
Do you understand me?
Do I understand you?
Yes, sir. Sergeant.
Take your toy and get back to bed.
Come on.
Good night, sir. Sergeant.
Good morning.
A Wilhelm Lebern?
Yes.
He came in, a couple of days ago.
Wilhelm died yesterday.
He's still here, if you would like to see him.
No. No, it's not necessary.
Thanks.
Get up, boys!
Stand up!
Line up!
Fall in!
At ease!
I have good and bad news.
The good thing is, I just visited Wilhelm.
He is feeling better.
They are taking good care of him,
and he will live.
You should greet him.
He will go home soon.
The bad news is that
we are behind schedule.
For the rest of the week we need to
disarm eight mines an hour.
Is that understood?
Yes, sir. Sergeant.
I can't hear you!
Yes, sir. Sergeant!
Good.
We depart in ten minutes.
Finish up eating.
As soon as I get home,
I will have beer and girls.
Yeah? Do you have a girlfriend back home?
No, I'll go straight out and get one.
Won't you be visiting your parents first?
They can wait.
What is your plan?
Make a lot of money, right?
Namely with my friend.
And what work would that be?
As masons, of course.
The Reich needs to be rebuilt.
That will be our task.
Werner, Ernst and sons.
And sons?
Our sons will take over the company.
Sounds better, when we use 'and sons'.
We own the company and no one would
detect that there are no sons.
Good idea! 'Ludwig and Sons'.
Sounds great, right?
Yes. Almost as good as
'Werner, Ernst and Sons'.
Shut up! This is heavy.
Gently, I said!
How many anti-tank mines are there?
44. Sir, Sargent.
Count them again.
2, 4, 6, 8, 10, 12...
14, 16, 18, 20, 22, 24, 26...
44. Sir, Sargent.
And the S mines?
16. Sir, Sargent.
Count them again.
What shall we call it?
Benny. He's called Benny.
Benny, Benny, Benny.
No, it shall be called Timmy.
No.
Is it because of the color?
What has Timmy got to do with black?
It just sounds black.
Benny is fine.
Lets call it...
Tim Benny.
Tim is its first name.
Benny is its last name.
No. No, my friend.
Come on, Tim Benny.
Look at the purple color.
A beautiful insect.
What kind of insect is it?
A six-legger.
A bark beetle.
No.
Benny Tim, the bark beetle.
Benny Tim, the six-legged bark beetle.
Yes.
Benny Tim, the six-legger?
So back to bed, boys.
Sebastian.
Everyone here?
Are you all here?
Yes, sir. Sergeant.
Stop! Look at him!
Close your mouth!
Stop!
Close as your mouth!
Stop! Stop it!
Shoot the bastard right between the eyes!
Gentlemen?
Look, how Nazi boys care of each other.
One two...
Up with the head!
Gentlemen, look here.
Please! Please, I need these boys.
Who the fuck are you?
Sergeant Carl Rasmussen.
This is my Unit.
My assignment is to clean the beach.
I need these boys.
I need all of them.
Needs them to work.
Fucking Danes.
Go inside, boys.
Come, Ludwig.
Ludwig. Go and wash him.
Hey!?
What the hell are you doing, Ebbe?
I just got them up and running.
Do you know, I don't think there was an order,
to steal food for the Germans from the kitchen.
I'll let myself and my dog when I want.
People talk. Pain in the ass.
Isn't that you?
No, but isn't it strange.
You have to steal food,
when we pay the farm
for your room and boarding.
Do you hear what I'm saying?
Look at me when I talk to you.
You could have told me,
I would get small boys.
It changes the situation a little.
I don't think it does.
If they are old enough to go to war,
they are old enough to clean up.
The boys have no idea what is going on.
No, but you must teach them that, Carl.
That's why you're here.
You haven't started liking them, right?
No.
Remember what they did.
Better them than us.
Could you help me get some
experienced men to my unit?
Shit!
Ludwig, stop!
Ludwig! There are two mines
on top of one another!
Stop! There are two mines
Werner! Stop!
I got you now, you little bugger.
Werner! Werner, where are you?
Werner! Werner!
Werner, where are you?
Ernst, sit down.
Werner? Werner!
Werner, where are you?
Say something!
Ernst, calm down.
Get off me!
Take it easy.
We must look for him!
Get off me!
Hold him down.
Werner!
Hold him down. Hold him down.
Calm down.
Take it easy, kid.
That's good.
Out now, boys.
Sebastian, out.
You have to sleep.
No. Take it easy.
We must look for Werner.
We'll look for Werner tomorrow.
Now you need to sleep.
Come on.
I will find Werner first.
We must get down to the beach.
I would have saved him, but he ran away.
We must find him.
He slept there.
I can't fall asleep without him.
Come on.
No. You have to sleep.
We'll look for him tomorrow.
Tomorrow? That sounds good.
When we find Werner...
I'll take him to Germany,
and build it all up again.
We'll build it all up.
The country is in ruins.
It needs to be rebuilt.
Masons...we have to be masons.
It's a good job.
Sir. Sergeant...
Don't hate him.
I don't.
No. Lie down.
Relax. You have to sleep now.
If you knew him as I did,
that would have helped.
I lied to you.
Wilhelm did not survive.
I know, sir. Sergeant.
It was best that way, so that we could
continue with the mine clearance.
So that we may go home one day.
Perhaps.
Don't worry. I won't take it from you.
Does the cross help you?
You can try it on, sir. Sergeant.
No.
Come on, sir. Sergeant.
Just try.
No.
I mean it, sir. Sergeant. Try.
My father gave it to me.
He always did like that and
I would startle every time.
That's why I have it on all the time.
Is your father alive?
I don't know.
Sebastian.
Hermann.
Rodolf.
August.
Johann.
Come, Friedrich.
Helmut, you're on our team.
Come, Helmut! Wake up!
Well, Helmut! Such!
Shoot!
August! I can't do it alone!
I need some help here!
Not again, you idiot!
It's football, not handball.
Down to earth, thank you.
Ludwig, come here!
We play on!
Who is that?
A new one.
Hello.
He must join the unit.
Where is Sergeant Rasmussen?
There he is. But I can take him with me.
My name is Ludwig.
Josef Becker.
Albert Brauer.
Come on. We have the day off.
What's your name?
Tell me.
Take it easy.
Stay there.
It will all be good.
One, two, three! Run!
Morbach has beaten the world record!
Look here!
The first goal was fantastic.
Next time we will win.
Come on. Come on.
Do you think?
Here, Otto. Come on. Come on.
Here. Hopti. Come on. Come on.
The water was lovely.
We have some beautiful dunes.
Yes. You must explore.
Soldier Ludwig Haffke.
You were responsible for field 7, right?
Yes, sir. Sergeant.
Everything has been accounted for.
1,200 mines were buried, 1200 were found, disarmed and accounted for.
But you have counted wrong, right?
No, I counted them twice.
1,200 mines were buried and
1200 mines were removed.
Get the ball.
Get the ball!
Like a dog! With your mouth!
Good dog. Very good dog.
Get the ball. Quick!
Without the hands! Use your mouth!
Good dog.
Good dog. Yeah? Good dog.
Good dog. Sit!
Bark!
Woof, sir. Sergeant.
What?
Woof.
Louder.
Bark! Louder!
Woof.
Is there anything you want to say?
What? Is there?
Anything you want to say? Huh?
Maybe...
Please stop, sir. Sergeant.
Idiot!
You're all idiots!
I have a bunch of German idiots! Do you hear?
Each and every one of you!
How can I now guarantee the beach is safe?
Tell me!
Sir. Sargent, we could count them again
to see if the numbers match.
If the numbers match?
What do I need the numbers for now? Huh?
What should we use it for?
What for? Huh?
Can you guarantee the beach is safe?
Can you?
No, sir. Sergeant!
Then keep your mouth shut!
I've been too kind to you.
That's the problem.
And you got used to it!
From now on you go along.
Arm in arm.
Next to each other.
Through all the cleared fields.
I must assure myself there are no mistakes!
It was a mistake to trust you.
But it's over now.
Is that understood?
Yes, sir. Sergeant!
You might as well put us up
against the wall and shoot us.
Do you have something to say, soldier?
Are you laughing?
Do you think I'm funny?
Laughing are you, soldier?
No, sir. Sergeant!
Why are you laughing then?
Why are you laughing?
Are you a man?
Yes, sir. Sergeant!
Are you a soldier?
So act like a soldier!
Is that clear?
Yes, sir. Sergeant!
You still think I'm funny?
No, sir. Sergeant.
Pull yourself together!
Man up!
Is there anyone who has something to say?
Tell me now.
Excellent. Forward march!
Come on! Forward march!
Through all the cleared fields!
Centimeter by centimeter!
Until we are absolutely sure!
Let's run away, before we all die.
Are you deaf?
Did you just find yourselves in it?
I rather, the British shoot us.
We'll be here until we're done.
Then we go home.
The sergeant said we go
home when we're done.
The sergeant? You think, your friend,
the sergeant would keep his word?
Continue this death march,
please, please please!
But don't tell me what to do!
And what happens to us,
when he realizes you're gone?
I can't allow it.
It's not your decision!
I'm out of here!
You stay here!
A fat-head you are!
He hates you, just as he hates us all!
Maybe you can make sergeant like us?
Take him!
Tie him!
Tie him up, I said!
Get off me!
Damned traitors!
Get off me! Get off me!
Keep your mouth shut.
Carl! Carl!
Where's the sergeant? Where's the sergeant?
Help! Help! My little girl!
My little girl! Help me!
Help! My little girl!
Elisabeth! Elisabeth!
Sit down, honey.
Someone will come help you.
Wake up!
Ernst, where are the others?
Wake up, kid!
Hey? Where are the others?
Did they run away?
You must be seated. Be seated.
You must sit still.
Shortly one of the boys
will come get you out.
Ernst!
Hi there.
Did she heal?
Here?
Did you know Werner?
He's a good brother.
He looks like me on a bullet.
I would do anything for him.
It's all good. It's all good.
Ernst, give her to me.
Come here, Ernst.
Ernst, come please.
Ernst, come here.
Ernst, come here!
Ernst. What are you doing?
Ernst, came back.
Come on, Ernst.
What are you doing?
Come back.
Wipe your eyes.
Repeat with me, 'It will soon be over'.
It will soon be over.
I'm coming home soon.
Okay?
Yes.
Stop crying.
I need you. The other needs you. Okay?
Be strong. Can you do it?
Yes. I can do that.
You are strong.
I'm strong.
Say it again.
I'm coming home soon.
It will soon be over.
Thanks.
Gustav?
Yes.
What are you going to do,
when you go home?
Eat! I just need to eat.
My mother is the best cook in Berlin.
I'm tired of the Danish pigswill.
You must invite us to your home.
Yes, come to Oranienburger Strasse in Berlin,
and you will get potatoes, meat and gravy.
The best.
Yes, the best.
Bloody hell!
Go.
Sit down.
What do you want?
We need more experienced people at Skallingen.
Yes, but I need them at Ringkobing.
Yes, please. It's not you, I'm talking about.
What are we talking about?
Your German boys.
We need them down there.
People, who can die like flies.
The mines have budged.
It's a place of chaos.
We need experienced Germans.
I wish I could help you,
but they have been sent home.
Mm. That I heard.
Four out of 14 made it.
But they will not be sent back.
I promised, they can go home when done.
And we're done.
All German soldiers must stay,
until all mines are cleared.
And I mean, all.
Ebbe?
I ask you to send those boys home.
Just let them go.
They will die down there.
I understand, Carl.
But I can't. The Order has been given.
It's just four boys!
Now you hear what I say!
If I hear anymore about those boys,
I'll shoot them myself one by one.
They are not good people.
You don't know what is on their conscience.
You lied to me, right from day one.
They are little boys.
Little boys who cry for their mothers,
when they get scared or blowup arms and legs.
The Germans, Carl.
The order has been given.
Find yourself out.
Thank you for today, Carl.
Shut up!
Ebbe...
That would be all, Carl.
We assume, there are 72,000 German mines,
buried here at Skallingen.
Some of you may have had the luxury,
to detail available cards.
Here at Skallingen we don't have such cards.
Helmut Morbach?
Yes.
Rodolf Selke?
Ludwig Haffke?
Yes.
Sebastian Schumann?
Come up.
Come on! Come up!
Get out! All of you.
Come on. Out!
You must go that way.
The boundary's about 500 meters from here.
And you will be in Germany.
Run.
Run!
After the war, over 2000 German prisoners were forced to clear
more than 1.5 million land mines from the Danish west coast.
Almost half of them died or were severely injured.
Many of them were just very young boys.